No, you can't sleep here!
Hayır, burada uyuyamazsın!
I'll be fine. Just fine.
Bir şey olmaz, olmaz.
Just leave me here.
Beni burada bırak.
You left her there.
Onu orada bıraktın!
Isn't that right? You left your mother there.
Değil mi? Anneni orada bıraktın.
The next day, you were notified that your mother froze to death.
Sonraki gün annenin donarak öldüğü haberini aldın
But this is what you thought then, "It wasn't my fault."
ama o an şöyle düşündün, "Benim suçum değil.
"I only did that because she asked me to leave her there."
Onu bırakmamı istediği için onu bıraktım sadece"
You're exactly right. It wasn't your fault.
Sonuna kadar haklısın. Senin suçun değildi.
These people wanted to die, so you simply let them.
O insanlar ölmek istedi ve sen de onları terk ettin.
You didn't do anything wrong. What you did was right.
Yanlış bir şey yapmadın. Sen doğru olanı yaptın.
You released them from the misery of life.
Onları hayatın ızdırabından kurtardın.
Eva too. She wants to die as well.
Eva'yı da. O da ölmek istiyor.
Just then, the devil came.
İşte o an iblis geldi.
I didn't look at the devil as we passed by one another.
İblis yanımdan geçerken onun yüzüne bakmadım.
Don't look. Don't you dare look.
Bakma. Sakın ha bakma.
I repeated that to myself like a child would.
Bir çocuk gibi kendi kendime bunu tekrarladım.
Eva too. She wants to die as well.
Eva'yı da. O da ölmek istiyor.
Please kill me!
Lütfen öldür beni!
Just leave me here.
Beni burada bırak.
Kenzo…
Kenzo.
I won't be part of the devil's plans.
İblisin planlarının bir parçası olmayacağım
Because nobody…
çünkü kimse
wants to die.
ölmek istemez.
Where's the woman?
Kadın nerede?
Eva's gone.
Eva gitti.
Where did you take her?
Onu nereye götürdün?
I got rid of her.
Ondan kurtuldum.
Don't lie, Martin. It's not too late.
Yalan söyleme Martin. Çok geç değil.
I ain't lying.
Yalan söylemiyorum.
How pathetic.
Çok acınası bir şey.
What is?
Ne?
Losing your life over a woman.
Bir kadın yüzünden hayatından olmak.
Are you awake?
Uyanık mısın?
FIVE MINUTES EARLIER
BEŞ DAKİKA ÖNCE
They're here.
Geldiler.
They just pulled up outside.
Dışarıda araçlarını park ettiler.
It's only a matter of time now.
Artık an meselesi.
I stole a maid's uniform from here.
Buradan hizmetli üniforması çaldım.
Put it on and escape out the back.
Onu giy ve arkadan kaç.
What about you?
Sen ne olacaksın?
If we tried to walk out of here together, they'd see us for sure and catch us.
Buradan birlikte kaçmaya çalışsak bizi kesin görüp yakalarlar.
But you'll be killed if you don't escape!
Ama kaçmazsan seni öldürürler.
If I'm alone, I'll manage somehow.
Tek başıma bir şekilde hallederim.
There's a note on the desk. Go to the place written on it.
Masada bir not var. Notta yazan yere git.
It's Tenma's hotel.
Tenma'nın oteli.
Hurry up and change.
Çabuk, üzerini değiştir.
I'll wait for you at Frankfurt Central Station.
Frankfurt Merkez Garı'nda seni bekleyeceğim.
Let's escape together.
Birlikte kaçalım.
Don't be ridiculous. This is no time for joking!
Saçmalama. Şaka yapacak vakit yok.
Listen! Going to Tenma is how you'll be saved and it's what you want!
Bana bak, canını kurtarmanın yolu Tenma'yla gitmek. İstediğin de buydu.
That's an order! Now go!
Bu bir emirdir, şimdi git.
I don't take orders from you.
Senden emir alacak değilim.
Just kidding.
Şaka yapıyorum.
I'm going.
Gidiyorum.
Good.
Güzel.
Don't do anything stupid and get yourself killed.
Aptalca bir şey yapıp canından olma.
I'm not getting myself killed for you.
Senin için canımdan olacak değilim.
Bye.
Hoşça kal.
That's right. I don't owe her anything.
Evet, ona hiçbir borcum yok.
I don't need to go this far for her.
Onun için bu kadar ileri gitmeme gerek yok.
One.
Bir.
Two.
İki.
Three.
Üç.
Four.
Dört.
I'm surprised I survived.
Sağ kaldığıma şaşırdım.
Frankfurt Central Station, huh?
Frankfurt Merkez Garı demek.
Out of bullets.
Mermim bitti.
Guess my luck just ran out.
Sanırım şansım tükendi.
Goddamn you…
Lanet olası…
Aim for the head, dammit!
Kafaya nişan alsana lan.
Four people were killed
Frankfurt, Sossenheim banliyösündeki Regon Moteli'nde yaşanan silahlı çatışmada
It's believed to be infighting among gangs.
Çeteler arası çatışma olduğu düşünülüyor. Polis soruşturmaya…
Robbie…
Robbie.
Did you hear that?
Bunu duydun mu?
My legend grows.
Namım yayılıyor.
Robbie!
Robbie.
Now for the next news item.
Şimdi haberlere geçelim.
We're here, Martin.
Geldik Martin.
Frankfurt Station?
Frankfurt Garı'na mı?
Hey… Doctor…
Selam doktor.
I've done all the first aid I can.
Yapabileceğim tüm ilk yardımı yaptım.
I can't do anything else here. You need to go to a hospital.
Burada başka bir şey yapamam. Hastaneye gitmelisin.
No way.
Mümkün değil.
I already know…
Kurtulma şansım olmadığını
I don't have a chance.
zaten biliyorum.
Eva…
Eva…
Where's Eva?
Eva nerede?
What about Eva?
Eva'ya ne olmuş?
Didn't she… come here?
Buraya gelmedi mi?
What are you laughing for, you moron?
Ne gülüyorsun geri zekâlı?
No more talking.
Artık konuşma.
I have to.
Mecburum.
You have to listen to me, Dr. Tenma.
Beni dinlemek zorundasın Dr. Tenma.
I don't know where to start.
Nereden başlayacağımı bilmiyorum.
I've learned… way too much.
Çok fazla şey öğrendim.
The experiments… of the Red Rose Mansion are…
Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'deki deneyler
still happening.
hâlâ devam ediyor.
I see… you understand what that means.
Bunun ne anlama geldiğini biliyorsun sanırım.
And that devil… he's got himself an apprentice now.
Ve o iblis kendine bir çırak buldu.
That guy… he's trying to create a dictator.
O adam bir diktatör yaratmaya çalışıyor.
Which guy?
Hangi adam?
The guy with glasses.
Gözlüklü adam.
The survivor of… the Red Rose Mansion…
Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'den sağ çıkan adam.
Petr Čapek.
Petr Čapek.
That guy… he's trying to control the devil.
O adam iblisi kontrol etmeye çalışıyor
But the devil… he's way too powerful and dangerous.
ama iblis çok güçlü ve tehlikeli.
The Jahreszeit Hotel… Room 606…
Jahreszeit Hotel, 606. oda.
That's where the devil's apprentice is.
İblisin çırağı orada.
But don't look the devil in the eye.
Ama iblisin gözlerine bakma.
Don't ever do the devil's bidding.
İblisin buyruğunu sakın ama sakın yapma.
Nobody wants to die.
Kimse ölmek istemez.
Martin!
Martin.
I… am happy.
Mutluyum.
I don't have to see the devil anymore.
Artık iblisi görmem gerekmeyecek.
Eva… is at Frankfurt Central Station…
Eva, Frankfurt Merkez Garı'nda.
She's probably…
Muhtemelen
bought tickets for two…
iki kişilik bilet almıştır.
to go as far, far away…
Mümkün olduğunca uzağa
as possible.
gitmek için.
Is Eva waiting there for you?
Eva orada seni mi bekliyor?
Protect Eva… for me.
Eva'yı benim için kurtar.
Protect Eva…
Eva'yı koru…
Don't die…
Ölme.
You have to go to the station.
Gara gitmek zorundasın.
Don't die!
Ölme!
You're going to be there quite a while if you're waiting for the first train.
İlk treni bekliyorsan burada epey bekleyeceksin.
Are you waiting for someone?
Birini mi bekliyorsun?
I bet it's a man.
Eminim bir erkektir.
I've worked at this station so long, I can usually tell.
Uzun süredir bu garda çalışıyorum. Genelde anlarım.
Then can you tell whether he'll come or not?
O zaman gelip gelmeyeceğini söyleyebilir misin?
I can't tell you that. I'm no fortune teller, after all.
Onu söyleyemem. Medyum değilim sonuçta.
But having someone to wait for is happiness.
Ama birini beklemek mutluluk demektir.
Whether they come or not.
O kişi gelse de gelmese de.
Happiness?
Mutluluk mu?
That's right.
Aynen.
At my age, you don't get feelings like that so much.
İnsan benim yaşıma gelince bu tarz duygular pek hissetmiyor.
Happiness, huh?
Mutluluk, öyle mi?
Could this be the man you're waiting for?
Beklediğin adam bu olabilir mi?
Kenzo…
Kenzo.
Martin… is dead.
Martin
Looks like he's not who she was waiting for.
Beklediği adam o değilmiş sanırım.
He came to me to give me some very important information…
Sana çok önemli bir bilgi vermem için kalan son gücüyle
with the last bit of strength he had left.
beni buraya gönderdi.
You need to run away, now.
Kaçmak zorundasın, hem de hemen.
Eva…
Eva.
There's still time until the first train leaves.
İlk trenin kalkmasına daha zaman var.
Can you stay with me until then?
O ana dek yanımda kalır mısın?
Sure.
Tabii.
Are you sure you don't want a proper drink?
Düzgün bir içecek istemediğine emin misin?
Martin… He didn't like liquor.
Martin… Martin içki sevmezdi.
I see.
Anladım.
Here's to Martin.
Martin'e içelim.
It's been a while.
Uzun zaman oldu.
Yes.
Evet.
Are you eating properly?
İyi besleniyor musun?
You look pretty gaunt.
Biri deri bir kemik kalmışsın.
Yeah.
Evet.
This is so strange.
Çok tuhaf.
The two of us here holding a funeral for Martin.
İkimiz oturmuş, Martin'in yasını tutuyoruz.
He was a good guy.
İyi bir adamdı.
He was such a good guy, but I did terrible things to him.
Çok iyi bir adamdı ama ona çok kötü şeyler yaptım.
I made him wear the same kind of suit and necktie
Onu bir zamanlar sana verdiğim takım ve kravatın aynısını giymeye zorladım.
I'm so awful.
Çok kötü biriyim.
I'm the worst.
Berbat biriyim.
How come I'm still alive?
Nasıl oluyor da hâlâ hayattayım.
I lied about you to make you look guilty.
Seni suçlu göstermek için senin hakkında da yalan söyledim.
How come I'm still alive and well?
Nasıl oluyor da sapasağlam hayattayım?
Because Martin protected you.
Martin seni korudu da ondan.
Why protect me?
Beni neden korudu?
Why protect a woman like me?
Benim gibi bir kadını neden korudu?
"Nobody wants to die."
"Kimse ölmek istemez"
That's what Martin said.
Martin böyle dedi.
He said he was happy.
Mutlu olduğunu söyledi.
You were waiting for him at the station.
Garda onu bekliyordun.
He said that made him happy.
Bunun için mutlu olduğunu söyledi.
Munich…
Münih.
Go to Munich.
Münih'e git.
A psychiatrist friend of mine lives there.
Orada bir psikiyatrist arkadaşım var.
Dr. Reichwein?
Dr. Reichwein mı?
-You know him? -Yes.
-Onu tanıyor musun? -Evet.
For now, let Dr. Reichwein find a place for you to hide.
Şimdilik Dr. Reichwein sana saklanacak bir yer bulsun.
He'll treat you well.
Sana iyi bakar
And go to the police.
ve polise git.
Tell them that The Baby's organization here in Frankfurt is after you
Bebek'in Frankfurt'taki örgütünün
and that Roberto is after you.
ve Roberto'nun senin peşinde olduğunu söyle.
Tell them absolutely everything.
Onlara her şeyi anlat.
I'll tell them about you too, that you didn't kill anyone.
Seni de anlatacağım, kimseyi öldürmediğini anlatacağım.
That it was all done by Johan.
Her şeyi Johan'ın yaptığını.
I'll tell them everything, so come with me to Munich.
Onlara her şeyi anlatacağım, benimle Münih'e gel.
He's right here.
Burada.
What?
Ne?
He's very close.
Çok yakında.
You saw him at a party, right?
Onu partide gördün, değil mi?
Johan is right here.
Johan burada.
I've got to end this.
Buna bir son vermeliyim.
I cannot allow…
Martin'in başına gelenlerin başkasının başına gelmesine izin veremem.
You understand, right?
Anlıyorsun, değil mi?
I'm going to end this.
Buna bir son vereceğim.
I'll write a letter to Dr. Reichwein.
Dr. Reichwein'a mektup yazacağım.
I'll write to him about everything I know.
Ona bildiğim her şeyi yazacağım.
Kenzo…
Kenzo.
Okay, get going.
Tamam, git hadi.
But Kenzo…
Ama Kenzo…
You can help me
Münih'e gidip
by going to Munich and telling the police everything.
polise her şeyi anlatarak bana yardım edebilirsin.
I'm very pleased you brought us and Johan together.
Johan'la beni buluşturmana çok sevindim.
I appreciate it.
Sana minnettarım.
When we heard that someone who looked like him was here in Frankfurt,
Ona benzeyen birinin Frankfurt'a geldiğini duyduğumuzda
we asked you to identify him for us.
onu bizim için tespit etmeni istedik.
Sorry to bother you while you're eating. There's a call for you.
Kusura bakmayın, yemeğinizi bölüyorum. Size telefon var.
Got it.
Tamam.
Hello? It's me.
Alo, benim.
Johan?
Johan mı?
I see. Where's he at?
Anladım, nerede?
An apartment on Haldecker Street.
Haldecker Sokağı'nda bir dairede.
Johan…
Johan…
I can put an end to you too.
Senin de hayatına bir son verebilirim.
The Jahreszeit Hotel… Room 606…
Jahreszeit Hotel, 606. oda.
That's where the devil's apprentice is.
İblisin çırağı orada.
You're the one who wants a gun?
Silah isteyen sen misin?
Yeah.
Evet.
There are all kinds of guns.
Her türde silah var.
Give me your biggest one.
En büyük silahını ver.
A novice can't handle the big ones.
Çaylak biri büyük silah kullanamaz.
What are you going to shoot with it?
Ne vuracaksın?
A devil.
Bir iblis.
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
Alt yazı çevirmeni: Ömür Gencer